<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
    <head>
        <episode>DIVIDE AND CONQUER</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard1">Guard 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard3">Guard 3</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard8">Guard 8</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Robin">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Starfire">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Raven">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Cyborg">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Prisoners">Prisoners</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="385901">385901</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guards">Guards</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Prisoner1">Prisoner 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Prisoner2">Prisoner 2</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Slade">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Plasmus">Plasmus</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: an overhead view of a prison at night. Smoke pours from behind the
                outer wall and the shattered front entrance, as well as from a spot on the bridge
                that leads to the complex. If these clues are not enough to indicate that something
                very bad is going on, the blaring klaxons and sirens settle the point decisively.
                Zoom in very slowly and cut to inside the entrance; three guards run in through it.
                Each has a number emblazoned on his shoulder-1, 3, 8.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Code red! Cellblock Nine! Move out!</sp>
            <sd>The other two follow orders, and he brings up the rear. They run in a short distance
                and then slow to a walk, weapons at the ready.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Main yard secure.</sp>
            <sd>Something very large is thrown down in front of them to roll a little bit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Guard3">Guard 3</spkr>There he is!</sp>
            <sd>They advance.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Guard8">Guard 8</spkr>He’ll free the criminals!</sp>
            <sd>They level their weapons.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Fire!</sp>
            <sd>Their target has already bashed a large hole through the wall of the cellblock and
                is on the way in-he threw part of the torn-out section at them. Seen from the back,
                this creature is at least ten feet tall, very blocky, and appears to be built
                entirely of concrete. We have just met the villain Cinderblock. Laser blasts from
                the guards strike the edges of the hole he has made, while a few connect with his
                back and others fly past. He turns to them, revealing an equally blocky face with
                small red eyes. The shots are having no discernible effect on him. Voicing a grating
                roar, he raises one massive foot and stomps the ground; this produces a long fissure
                that throws debris and dust into the three guards’ faces to spoil their aim. Cut to
                inside the cellblock. He moves in ans stops upon hearing the next words.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> You know, Cinderblock,
                normally the bad guys break out of jail.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> And I can think of five good
                reasons why you don’t want to break in.</sp>
            <sd>Cut to Robin; he leaps across the floor and lands in a crouch.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>voice over</sd> One!</sp>
            <sd>Now Starfire swoops and lands, looking sidelong at the camera from over her
                shoulder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over</sd> Two!</sp>
            <sd>Beast Boy, as a tiger, lunges in. When he comes down, he has taken human form except
                for his head and one arm; he quickly restores these as well.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>voice over</sd> Three!</sp>
            <sd>Next, Raven drops in and gets ready to cast a spell.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>voice over</sd> Four!</sp>
            <sd>Finally Cyborg jumps in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>voice over</sd> Five!</sp>
            <sd>The Titans stand ready for battle now.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>No matter how you do the math, it all adds up to you
                going down. So, are you going to go quietly...</sp>
            <sd>Pan to Cyborg.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>…or is this gonna get loud?</sp>
            <sd>Cinderblock roars and barrels straight toward them.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>
            <sd>They charge; Beast Boy becomes a hawk to fly behind Raven and Starfire. Yelling, the
                five heroes and the one oversized villain hurtle toward one another. Freeze frame
                and snap to black.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act 1</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: Cinderblock continuing his rush. The Titans do likewise. After a few
                seconds, the view shifts to letterbox, with the image in the top half of the screen.
                Silhouettes of the two sides charge ahead, after which the view returns to
                fullscreen and Robin lands a solid kick that staggers the foe. He turns around just
                in time to catch a double dose of starbolts in the back, courtesy of Starfire. Now
                Cyborg aims a right hook; even though Cinderblock stops it, he is still driven back
                by the impact.</sd>

            <sd>Beast Boy dives in and rakes his talons across the concrete body time after time,
                forcing Cinderblock to run to another corner. Raven puts herself in his path and
                levitates a section of the floor, tilting it up until it stands vertical. She rises
                out of the way an instant before he crashes through this improvised barrier, then
                flies away as Robin, Cyborg, and Starfire rush him.</sd>

            <sd>One giant backhand leaves only Starfire still in motion; the other two have been
                knocked away. She throws a couple of starbolts, but is then grabbed in those two
                enormous hands and pulled in with a little gasp for a face-to-face look at
                Cinderblock. A smile comes over her face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am sorry to disappoint you, but I am stronger
                than I look.</sp>
            <sd>She proves it by breaking his hold and delivering a high kick that drives him back
                against the wall. A cry from the o.c. Beast Boy-hawk is heard, and he swoops in
                again; in an instant, he has hit the ground and transformed into a tyrannosaurus
                rex. Cinderblock stands pat before his thundering charge and knocks him back with a
                single left hook.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion-</sp>
            <sd>She cuts off the incantation with a sharp, shocked gasp as she discovers Beast Boy’s
                shadow falling over her and sees him dropping from above. Overhead view; his
                panicked yell from o.c. is accompanied by the shadow’s change to human form. He
                falls on her like a ton of bricks and is the first to get up, shaking his head to
                clear it. Raven stands a moment later and grits her teeth in anger before getting
                herself under control. A lock of hair falls over her face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>sheepishly</sd>Heh… watch out for falling
                dinosaurs?</sp>
            <sd>She gives him a hard glance and blows the hair aside.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I’m gonna leave you alone now.</sp>
            <sd>He bugs out. Cinderblock chuckles to himself and starts to cross the area, but Robin
                jumps onto his neck and tries to put him in a headlock. Stumbling about at random,
                the stone behemoth tears a girder loose from the wall. A chunk of concrete from the
                floor goes with it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Thrashing only makes me hold tighter!</sp>
            <sd>Cinderblock raises the girder for a swing back over his shoulder to hit Robin, but
                misses when the Boy Wonder jumps away just in time; he only clocks himself in the
                head. Cyborg looks at another girder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Now there’s an idea.</sp>
            <sd>He rips it free and charges. Letterbox: he and Cinderblock, in silhouette, swing at
                each other, the entire screen flashing blue every time their makeshift clubs
                collide. Cyborg steadily gains ground on the enemy. Fullscreen: they struggle at
                close quarters, and Cinderblock pushes Cyborg back in preparation for a mighty
                swing. It connects, sending the Titan and his girder skidding across the floor.
                Starfire floats down from above; Cinderblock gets ready to let her have it, but the
                quick flash of a starbolt causes the steel to heat and soften in his hands. He
                grunts in surprise, and she laughs as Raven looks on.</sd>

            <sd>Cinderblock grunts and runs off down the corridor, heading deeper into the prison.
                Cyborg is still flat on his back, but gets up with a helping hand from Robin and
                dusts himself off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Want to give this guy the Sonic Boom?</sp>
            <sd>Cyborg smiles and converts his arm to sonic cannon mode.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I got the Sonic if you got the Boom.</sp>
            <sd>Their three teammates regroup and look off down the corridor. Cut to Cinderblock,
                still heading farther in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> Yo, Rockhead!</sp>
            <sd>He stops and turns around to find Robin and Cyborg running straight at him. They
                peel off to opposite sides and go up the walls, then jump toward each other as the
                cannon warms up. Whatever they were planning goes badly wrong, however, as their
                feet get tangled up and they are left spinning out of control in midair. Finally
                they fly apart and Cyborg crashes into the wall. His cannon goes off, producing a
                blast of sound that engulfs Beast Boy and Starfire. Robin slams against the other
                wall; a disc in his hand slides away and detonates at Raven’s feet.</sd>

            <sd>Cinderblock is completely unscathed by the fireworks and clumps away, smashing
                straight through one wall after another in his path. Prisoners step out to look
                after the lumbering colossus, then start to sprint out the same way he came in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#VariousPrisoners">Various prisoners</spkr>Hey, hey, look at this. It’s
                freedom!...Let’s do it!...Let’s get outta here!...Yeah!</sp>
            <sd>Other voices are heard among these words. Cut to Robin, on his feet and rubbing his
                head; the commotion reaches him from around the corner, and soon a throng of
                escaping prisoners is coming straight at him. He whips out his fighting staff and
                extends it to full length, and he, Raven, Beast Boy, and Starfire get ready to throw
                down. Letterbox: silhouettes of the four Titans and the prisoners against a red
                background. As the latter are caught by surprise, the former let them have it. Beast
                Boy resumes his T-rex form to scare the living bejesus out of them.</sd>

            <sd>Fullscreen: close-up of a sign on a cell door. "Prisoner 385901-Absolute Silence!"
                Cinderblock’s footsteps rumble from o.c. and his shadow appears over the sign.
                Inside the cell, which is extremely large, a cylindrical glass tank of liquid is
                suspended from the ceiling. Within it is the figure of a man, floating erect and
                clad only in a pair of underwear. The door is smashed off its hinges, and
                Cinderblock enters and approaches the tank. In close-up, the man is seen to be
                perhaps in his thirties, very thin, with a shaved head. He is asleep and snoring
                loudly.</sd>

            <sd>Cinderblock rips the entire tank away from the ceiling-mounted apparatus that holds
                it; broken hoses spew liquid and gases about the cell. He then punches a hole in the
                floor and jumps through it to make his escape, pulling the tank after himself. Even
                though the container gets briefly stuck and has to be yanked forcibly through the
                hole, 385901 does not so much as stir in his sleep.</sd>

            <sd>Wipe to just outside the entrance of the cellblock as two prisoners run out in a bid
                for freedom.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Prisoner1">Prisoner 1</spkr>Let’s go, let’s go!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Prisoner2">Prisoner 2</spkr>I think we’re gonna make it!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Prisoner1">Prisoner 1</spkr>Yeah!</sp>
            <sd>Their perspective: they approach the smashed gate in the outer wall-which is
                promptly closed when the pieces fly back into the frame. Back to the prisoners, who
                stop in their tracks.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Prisoner1 #Prisoner2">Prisoners 1, 2</spkr>Huh?</sp>
            <sd>Snap to black, which resolves into a swirling vortex in front of the gate. It
                recedes to nothing as Raven floats in through the barrier-repaired by her
                telekinesis.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Think again.</sp>
            <sd>Wipe to the corridor, near the holes Cinderblock smashed through the walls. Guards
                keep watch as the prisoners return to their cells, their arms shackled behind their
                backs. Pan from here to the Titans; Beast Boy is now a gorilla, but he quickly
                assumes human form.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Jailbreak? I don’t see any jailbreak.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>None of us would have seen one if Cyborg hadn’t
                messed up!</sp>
            <sd>He looks away.</sd>
            <sd>Sight gag: each speaker’s head grows a size when he speaks, then shrinks back to
                normal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Me? I messed up nothing!</sp>
            <sd>with great force; Robin’s cape blows back</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You got in my way!</sp>
            <sd>He looks away as well.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>turning back</sd> You were too far forward, and
                Cinderblock got away because of it!</sp>
            <sd>An angry little spark pops up on his temple during the end of this and then winks
                out when his head deflates. Now the background goes red and the sight gag becomes
                more exaggerated, with the non-speaker shrinking a bit as he gets yelled at as
                well.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>turning back</sd> You saying this is my
                fault?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Want me to say it again?</sp>
            <sd>The sight gag ends. Sparks fly between both pairs of eyes before Starfire pops up
                between them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Stop! No more mean talking!</sp>
            <sd>They turn their backs on her and each other, and the normal background restores
                itself as Beast Boy speaks up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah. If you two are gonna fight, we need time
                to sell tickets.</sp>
            <sd>He backs off; Raven steps up.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Cinderblock escaped. No amount of yelling will change
                that. So stop acting like idiots, and let’s go home.</sp>
            <sd>Cyborg and Robin throw each other a disdainful glance from over their
                shoulders.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin #Cyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr>Hmph!</sp>
            <sd>Their respective exhalations are visible in the air. Now they stride away, leaving
                the other Titans nonplussed.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>softly</sd> Loser.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>softly</sd> Jerk.</sp>
            <sd>Letterbox view: they whirl to face one another.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin #Cyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr>What did you say?!?</sp>
            <sd>Fullscreen: they go face to face. The background turns red again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Do you have a problem, Tin Man?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah! It’s four feet tall and smells like cheap
                hair gel!</sp>
            <sd>This hits him the wrong way. Cut to the others against the wall. Sight gag: they
                have become scared infants, with the pair’s shadows thrown across them as rough
                caricatures.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> Well, you’re an oversized klutz
                and your feet smell like motor oil!</sp>
            <sd>Beast Boy starts to cry.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> You’re bossy, you’re rude, you
                got no taste in music!</sp>
            <sd>The sight gag ends as the camera shifts to frame all five again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>I don’t even know why you’re on this team!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That makes two of us! I QUIT!!</sp>
            <sd>These two words leave the rest of the group staring wide-eyed in total shock.
                Letterbox, in the top third of the screen: his silhouette stalks away from theirs
                against a blue field, and Robin hangs his head. Fade to black as the sound of
                machinery makes itself heard.</sd>

            <sd>Fade in to a close-up of turning gears and dissolve to a series of other shots of
                heavy equipment hard at work-cams and pistons and crankshafts. Pan from the last
                view across a large enclosure illuminated chiefly by dim red light, then stop on a
                shadowy figure seated on a large chair atop a raised platform. No features can be
                seen except the glint of full-body armor and one eye, the left. An overhead fixture
                pours light down on the seat. This is Slade, though he will not be named for some
                time to come. In the harsh glare, the right side of the head and shoulder show a
                gray tint, while red-orange appears on the other side.</sd>

            <sd>Cinderblock stumps into the light and places the tank containing 385901 on the
                floor. When Slade speaks, his tone is even and measured.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Slade">Slade</spkr>Cinderblock. I see your mission was a success. Good.
                We will proceed with Phase Two. Wake him.</sp>
            <sd>The behemoth strains at the metal cap on the top end of the tank and manages to
                unscrew it, releasing thick clouds of vapor. When they clear, the occupant begins to
                stir from his slumber.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#385901">385901</spkr><sd>through glass, startled</sd> I’m...awake? I
                should never be awake! I’m only human when I’m sleeping!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Slade">Slade</spkr>But for what I have in mind, your human form is
                    useless.<sd>leaning forward</sd>I need Plasmus.</sp>
            <sd>The man’s form begins to swell and distort within the tank, causing the glass to
                bulge and finally shatter. What comes out is a mass of purplish slime that
                overwhelms the nearby Cinderblock, accompanied by more fumes from the liquid inside.
                When the view clears, the overhead light has gone out and the ooze has formed itself
                into a very large, roughly shaped humanoid with an extremely wide mouth and two tiny
                yellowish eyes-Plasmus, the form taken by 385901 whenever he is not asleep. The
                reason for the silence warning on his cell’s door is now abundantly clear. Plasmus
                comes forward and lets off a screeching roar. Fade to black.</sd>
        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act 2</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: the exterior of Titans Tower. It is now the next day. Ringing is heard
                over a telephone line, followed by the click of the call being answered.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>on answering machine</sd> This is Cyborg. I’m
                either in the gym, playing GameStation- <sd>Zoom in slowly.</sd> -or kicking bad-guy
                butt. Leave a message.</sp>
            <sd>Beep.</sd>
            <sd>Cut to the operations center. Starfire is at the kitchen counter, Raven is looking
                at a bank of monitors, and Beast Boy paces with a cell phone in hand-he made the
                call. Robin stands at the windows.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hello? Cy? Pick up! <sd>Pause.</sd> Come on,
                Cy, pick up! <sd>Close-up of Raven; he paces behind her.</sd> I know you’re there.
                The phone’s built in your arm!</sp>
            <sd>In this shot, we can now see that Starfire is mixing something in a bowl. Raven
                reaches up to press a key. Now Beast Boy hangs up disgustedly. Cut to an extreme
                close-up of Starfire, who holds up a spoonful of glop from her bowl.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Taste.</sp>
            <sd>Pull back; she is holding it out to Beast Boy, and she shoves it into his mouth
                without warning. It sends him into convulsions, which end with him on all fours and
                trying to keep from vomiting. Finally he spits out the mess and scrubs frantically
                at his tongue to remove the last fragments.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What is that? Cream of toenails?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Pudding of Sadness. <sd>taking a spoonful</sd>
                It is what the people of my planet eat when bad things happen.</sp>
            <sd>She eats it and is suddenly on the verge of blowing her own chow; after a monster
                effort, she gets it down and ends up having a fit as well. Raven continues checking
                the monitors as Starfire brings her the bowl.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Try. The displeasing taste will ease your
                troubled mind.</sp>
            <sd>Raven turns to her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>My mind is never troubled. People come, people go.
                It’s pointless to be upset about Cyborg.</sp>
            <sd>Her hair flies wildly about her face and all the monitors crack-a sudden flare-up of
                her powers, caused by the fact that she actually is upset about his absence. She
                does not notice the damage, as she is looking directly at Starfire’s wide-eyed
                expression.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>What?</sp>
            <sd>Letterbox, top half of the screen. Robin’s silhouette, against the sunlight through
                the top-floor windows, looks morosely out over Jump City as Starfire’s flies to him
                with her horrid concoction. Fullscreen: she holds the bowl out to him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Here, Robin. You must need this most of all
                since...well...</sp>
            <sd>She lets it hang.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>I’m fine.</sp>
            <sd>He turns away. Letterbox, top two-thirds of screen; his silhouette retreats from
                hers.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Who knows? Maybe we’re better off without him.</sp>
            <sd>Fullscreen: she lowers her bowl and gazes after him with obvious concern. Wipe to a
                close-up of him in the gym; he is punching something just o.c. with great vigor.
                Pull back to reveal the target as a heavy bag. He delivers a final roundhouse kick
                and slumps over, winded. Looking up, he sees his and Cyborg’s weight benches-the
                latter equipped with the sort of giant barbells only that Titan could lift.</sd>

            <sd>In the kitchen, Beast Boy hoists a stack of dirty plates onto the counter by the
                sink. Many others are already piled up there.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yo! Whose turn to do dishes?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> Cyborg.</sp>
            <sd>The green Titan cries out briefly in surprise like a monkey at this. Robin goes to
                the sink and starts to wash a plate. Dissolve to him on the couch in the operations
                center; he is now playing on the GameStation system and blasting enemy aircraft out
                of the sky. The screen is projected onto the windows.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Come on, come on...I’m not scared to take...no! Yeah!
                Got it! Just one more and...yes!</sp>
            <sd>Close-up of the screen, which flashes red and blue and shows the message
                "Cyborg-1,000,000."</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> New high score!</sp>
            <sd>Cyborg’s name is smashed away by Robin’s, and the score changes to 5,000,000.
                However, the Titan who set it is no longer elated by his achievement. Cut to the
                hall; he approaches the door of Cyborg’s room. It opens to show the interior, and
                the camera starts to swivel slowly around. Bookcase with pictures and a baseball on
                top, computer desk with a football by the monitor, trophy case in one rear corner,
                and areas for self-repair and diagnostics. A large inclined table with a footstop at
                its lower end is in the other rear corner-what the missing Titan uses for a
                bed.</sd>

            <sd>The camera comes full circle to Robin, who has taken a picture from the dresser and
                is looking at it. Close-up: it is of the pair, laughing and having a grand time.
                Pull back into the room.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>softly</sd> I’m sorry.</sp>
            <sd>An alarm shatters the silence. Cut to Starfire, Beast Boy, and Raven in the
                operations center, looking ahead at something o.c. with surprise. Cut to it: a map
                of Jump City projected on the window/screen, with a large flashing dot that slowly
                moves along. Robin runs in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Cinderblock strikes again?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You wish.</sp>
            <sd>Dissolve to a long shot of a chemical factory; it is now nighttime. Inside, jets of
                colored solutions shoot down from overhead nozzles and flow together in a pipeline
                that snakes across the factory floor. The mixture emerges from its other end and
                falls into a waiting barrel; pan from here to Plasmus at the free end of the
                conveyor on which it and others are resting. As the belt starts to move, he picks up
                each arriving barrel and guzzles it, growing a few feet taller after each of the
                first two. The third is hit with a starbolt before he can finish it; the remaining
                chemicals spill out the broken end, and he lifts the barrel to his eye to peer
                through it.</sd>

            <sd>His perspective, swiveling across the area. The four Titans are waiting for
                him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>That stuff can’t be good for you.</sp>
            <sd>Back to Plasmus, who throws the barrel aside and belches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Nice one!</sp>
            <sd>He roars and shoots gobbets of sludge from his body toward the heroes, who scatter
                to avoid being hit. Robin jumps and flips like mad, just barely staying ahead of the
                barrage, and lands on a crate near a mixing tank.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Star! Let him have it!</sp>
            <sd>She obliges with a starbolt that blows a hole clear through the creature’s
                chest.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>gasping</sd> Did I let him have too
                much?</sp>
            <sd>He sucks in a huge breath; the hole fills in.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I’m thinking not enough.</sp>
            <sd>Its hand balled into a fist, one gooey arm extends itself toward Starfire, who
                shrieks as Raven plows her out of the way.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>pulling a disc from his belt</sd> Maybe he just
                needs to chill.</sp>
            <sd>He scales the projectile at Plasmus; it freezes the long arm solid upon impact. The
                owner of said arm looks at it in surprise, then shatters it against an overhead
                pipe. Robin jumps for cover, while Beast Boy turns into a pterodactyl and lifts off.
                Starfire blazes away from above, driving Plasmus back a bit, and Beast Boy executes
                several punching strikes with his talons. The foe blocks these and retaliates by
                lashing out with many thick tentacles from the stump of his missing arm.</sd>

            <annot>Animation goof: He is seen to have two arms while backing up from her
                barrage.</annot>

            <sd>Both Titans cut and run to stay out of the mess. Starfire throws shots every which
                way to fend off the attack as Beast Boy does a few evasive maneuvers. Now Raven
                rises into the air.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>
            <sd>She levitates several barrels and launches them at Plasmus; they strike him in the
                chest, end first, and stick there. His arm now regrown,he gathers his strength and
                sends them right back, forcing her to dive for cover. Robin leaps in for a flying
                kick only to get that leg stuck in the mire, followed by his other leg and one hand
                when he tries more blows. He struggles to get loose.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Come on! Let me go, you giant zit!</sp>
            <sd>It only snarls and roars down at him before sending forth a huge jet of slime that
                carries him screaming along with it. The purple tide washes over Beast Boy-back to
                human form-as well. Dripping with it, Robin groans and gets up as Starfire rushes
                over.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Robin!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>I’m okay… sort of.</sp>
            <sd>He spits out a wad or two. Beast Boy, meanwhile, has made it partway to his feet;
                his eyes are watering profusely.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And I thought Star’s pudding tasted bad!</sp>
            <sd>A fresh howl from Plasmus’ direction refocuses the attention of all four Titans in a
                hurry. Cut to a fuzzy image of him that flickers as the camera pulls back a bit to
                show this as a giant monitor, with two silhouettes standing before it. One of
                them-large, muscular, armored-is Slade; the other is a shorter individual.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Slade">Slade</spkr>Disappointing.</sp>
            <sd>Cinderblock’s silhouette moves into the frame. Close-up of Slade and the shorter
                person-an elderly fellow, bald on top, in a white suit and tie and a black
                shirt.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Slade">Slade</spkr>With one Titan missing, this is almost too easy.
                    <sd>Extreme close-up of his eye.</sd> I was expecting more of a challenge.
                Cinderblock.</sp>
            <sd>Pull back. An overhead light shines down on him, enveloping the old man and part of
                Cinderblock. The latter can be seen holding some large piece of equipment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Slade">Slade</spkr>Begin Phase Three.</sp>
            <sd>An answering grunt, and Cinderblock stumps away. Fade to black.</sd>
        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act 3</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: an open area of the factory floor. A gush of Plasmus’ muck splatters
                down from above, and Starfire stands up within it and groans disgustedly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I feel like the underside of a Zornian muck
                beetle.</sp>
            <sd>Raven gets up next to her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Tell me about it.</sp>
            <sd>Beast Boy runs for his life as Plasmus pursues.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude, I am not on the menu!</sp>
            <sd>Robin’s birdarang sails into view trailing a long line behind it. This grappling
                hook flies around Plasmus’ legs to wrap them up; Robin is quick to arrive as well.
                He grabs the free end of the line and takes a few more turns around the giant.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Maybe the best way to take you down… <sd>pulling
                    mightily</sd> …is to tie you up!</sp>
            <sd>Beast Boy, now a rhinoceros, charges and scores a direct hit that sends Plasmus
                toppling backward to fall among a group of support columns. Starfire bends one over
                to pin him, and Raven does likewise with others. He struggles against these bonds as
                the four inspect the handiwork; Beast Boy is back in human form.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>We did it!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Nice work, team.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah. Didn’t think we’d pull it off
                without-</sp>
            <sd>Raven angrily socks him in the shoulder to cut him off. He lets off a surprised
                little sheep-like bleat, then laughs and sweats nervously. Robin checks a locator
                device briefly before tucking it away in his belt.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>We finished just in time. Cinderblock’s been spotted
                downtown. Come on!</sp>
            <sd>The four Titans turn to leave, but a loud gurgling noise from Plasmus’ direction
                stops Beast Boy. He turns back.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Huh?</sp>
            <sd>Cut to an overhead view of the trapped creature, panning slowly along his length, as
                he starts to ooze a bit under those girders. Back to a head-on view; his entire body
                flows together and free of the restraints, then shapes itself into a gigantic
                crab-like thing with one claw, an octopus-like appendage, and a snaky rear
                limb.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh… heads up.</sp>
            <sd>Now having formed a second crab claw, Plasmus rushes at the foursome; they burst out
                through a set of double doors. Cut to just outside as they make it through and slam
                the doors shut just in time, leaning against them with all their weight. Plasmus’
                snarling and pounding can be heard through the metal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Four against five. Not good odds.</sp>
            <sd>He is referring to the claws/beetles, octopus, snake, and body together-five
                battering rams to employ against the doors.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Forget the odds. We need a plan.</sp>
            <sd>The doors tremble even more violently under Plasmus’ assault, and he finally forces
                them partway open and pushes a tendril out, then another. Starfire screams as the
                opening grows wider and the head appears.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Separate!</sp>
            <sd>The doors are finally smashed open. Robin, Starfire, and Beast Boy go in three
                different directions among the machinery; the latter turns into a cheetah as he
                runs. Plasmus’ snake, separated from the rest of the body, chases Starfire; she
                turns in midair and bombards it with starbolts, but it lunges and catches her to
                drag her from the air. Beast Boy sprints along the floor, with one of the crab claws
                in hot pursuit. It opens wide and lashes out a long tongue that snares him. He
                breaks loose by turning into a gorilla, but is knocked off his feet by a flying
                tackle.</sd>

            <sd>Raven, meanwhile, flies along as the octopus chases on the ground. She exerts her
                powers over all the machinery here, causing the bolts and screws to fall out, and
                the loosened vessels topple into the aisle one after another. The octopus swerves
                and slides to miss several of them, but is finally hit broadside. She looks back
                smugly only to find that it has recovered and placed itself directly in front of
                her; there is only time for one shocked gasp before it rears up to strike.</sd>

            <sd>The only one left is Robin, who keeps going full steam among the other process
                equipment; the other crab claw is after him and not letting up. He reaches a set of
                double doors, and the screen snaps to black-the darkened area on the other side,
                which is illuminated as he hurls himself through and into space. Lurid green light
                rises from the direction of the floor. Something breaks his fall, and he finds
                himself carried along in midair as he rubs his head; pull back to show him standing
                on a moving conveyor belt above several large vats of glowing chemicals.</sd>

            <sd>The crab claw lands behind him and pulls back to strike. Robin has his staff out in
                a snap and delivers several blows that merely splatter through the purple goo. The
                end is caught and broken off, but he simply extends the other end to make up for the
                lost length and swings again. This time, his weapon is not only blocked but dashed
                from his hands to go spiraling over the vats. Going into classic kung fu mode, he
                backs up a few steps and lunges for a high kick.</sd>

            <sd>Cut to Starfire, still held fast by Plasmus’ snake portion. As she struggles, it
                wraps a coil around her head and squeezes itself together into a large ball. She
                bursts out of it after a moment and sees the main body perched on top of an
                equipment cabinet, lying in wait. Beast Boy-back in human form-and Raven are carried
                into view, still held by their respective captor body parts, and the snake reforms
                at the feet of one very frightened Tamaranean teenager. She recoils at its
                strike.</sd>

            <sd>Back to the conveyor. Robin steadily backs up before the opponent’s advance, and it
                soon throws itself on top of him to pin him to the belt’s surface. The Boy Wonder
                struggles mightily as both are swept toward the free end, which hangs over a
                bubbling vat. He goes partway over, then smiles wickedly and flips the claw backward
                off the precipice; however; he miscalculates and has to grab the corner of the belt
                to keep from going down with it. Close-up of this: the housing starts to pull loose,
                and a camera shift reveals why-the claw has seized one boot and is pulling with all
                its strength. Robin strains with all the power he can put into his one-handed grip,
                but the conveyor has had all it can take. His fingers slide away from the ripping
                material to leave him plummeting toward the last bath he will ever take.</sd>

            <sd>Out of nowhere, a familiar bionic arm shoots into view and grabs his wrist. The
                camera turns down from him to the surface of the vat, where the sludgy apparition is
                dissolving harmlessly after having fallen in. On the conveyor, Robin has been
                hoisted up by Cyborg, who stands behind him, and tries desperately to catch his
                breath.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>smiling</sd> I still got the Sonic if you still
                got the Boom.</sp>
            <sd>Robin returns the smile-the feud between the two has ended in a twinkling. On the
                factory floor, Plasmus’ other four body parts have reassembled themselves and the
                other three are nowhere to be seen. He laughs nastily, but stops short when Robin
                and Cyborg square off against him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin #Ccyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr>Teen Titans! Go!</sp>
            <sd>They go into the same sequence of moves they used while trying to pull off the Sonic
                Boom attack against Cinderblock inside the prison. This time, however, they do not
                get tangled up in midair, and Robin hurls an explosive disc while Cyborg fires his
                cannon. The combined effect of the two weapons is enough to blow Plasmus apart into
                small puddles of gunk; when the screen clears, we see 385901 dozing among the slop
                and snoring fitfully.</sd>

            <sd>Cut to Beast Boy and Raven, who sit up out of the remains of their captors, and pan
                to Starfire, who has already done likewise-they had been engulfed by the slime.
                Robin and Cyborg look down at the frail man who has just inflicted so much damage on
                the factory. Dissolve to them outside, watching as he is loaded onto a truck for the
                return trip to prison; he is contained in a new tank.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Look, uh… sorry about…</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>So… are we cool?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>smiling, holding out a fist</sd> Frosty.</sp>
            <sd>Robin smiles back as they tap fists. Pan to the other three Titans in the
                background.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You made up! Glorious! I wish to initiate a
                group hug.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Pass.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah, yeah, yeah, warm fuzzies all around. But
                we still gotta stop Cinderblock.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd> No, we don’t. <sd>Back to him
                    and Robin.</sd> Thought I’d bring a present, ‘case you were still mad.</sp>
            <sd>He gestures behind himself, and in response Cinderblock is hoisted up on a
                winch-with the equipment he had been carrying in Slade’s lair wrapped around his
                body to bind him. The stone villain grumbles angrily.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Thanks. But there is one thing that’s still bothering
                me.</sp>
            <sd>Raven, Beast Boy, and Starfire first react with surprise, then go wide-eyed in
                disbelief that anything could be bothering their leader at this point, given the
                events of the past few hours. Zoom in slowly on him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Breaking into jail? Using Plasmus to distract us? The
                whole plan seems to be a little too smart for Cinderblock.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I’ve been thinking the same thing.</sp>
            <sd>The other three are relieved; Beast Boy and Starfire sigh visibly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Someone must have been pulling the strings. But
                who?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Well, whoever they are-</sp>
            <sd>Letterbox, top half of screen: the Titans are silhouetted against the evening sky,
                with a full moon behind them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>-they’re no match for the Teen Titans.</sp>
            <sd>He and Robin trade a high five.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>I heard that!</sp>
            <sd>Fullscreen: dissolve to a close-up of a teacup and saucer on a table or ledge. A
                fist is slammed down, breaking them, after which a pair of white-gloved hands
                reaches down with a small broom and dustpan to sweep up the pieces. Pull back; it is
                the elderly man previously seen with Slade-a butler. He has a fresh cup, which he
                sets on the arm of his employer’s chair. Slade is once again seated and lit as
                before. Despite having just lashed out, his voice retains its control.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Slade">Slade</spkr>Next time my plans will succeed. <sd>Extreme close-up
                    of his eye; zoom in as it narrows.</sd> And the Titans will pay.</sp>
            <sd>Fade to black.</sd>

            <cue>End</cue>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>
